kamair.com 2016-01-23

# Kam Air - Privacy Policy

This website is owned and managed by Kam Air (trading as and hereinafter referred to as "Kam Air ").

Kam Air is committed to protecting the privacy of information you provide us on this website. This policy is applicable to Kam Air’s website only and does not cover any access you make to third party sites, even while using links from our Kam Air website.

We are responsible for the processing of any personal information you provide to this website and we are registered/approved where required in each country under the relevant data protection legislation of that country.

We take our responsibilities regarding the protection of personal information very seriously. This policy explains how we collect and use customer information and how we protect your privacy:  
Why do we ask for personal information?

When you use services provided on this website, you will be asked to provide certain information such as your name, contact details, travel documents details.

The personal information we request is necessary to allow us to process your flight booking. It is also required to register you on our website.

We need to know the names of all passengers travelling. If you are booking a flight on behalf of someone else, you must obtain their consent to use their personal information. We proceed on the basis that you have obtained this consent.

We may require the name and contact details of a third party whom we may contact in an emergency. It is your responsibility to ensure that the third party consents to the disclosure of the information provided for that purpose.

How we use your personal information

If you are a customer, the information you provide or that is obtained by us on this website, via our call center or a travel agent will be used by us and/or our affiliates to provide you and other customers (via post, email, telephone or otherwise) with information about new products and services and special offers we think you will find valuable. We may also inform you about new products and services and special offers of selected third parties, where you have registered to receive these.

If you are a candidate or user for recruitment, employment and/or human resources purposes, the information and/or data that you provide or that is obtained by us on this website or otherwise, will be used by us and/or our affiliates to process your query, request or application. We may also inform you about any relevant opportunities, products or services (including those of selected third parties), where you have registered to receive these.

We may contact you by post, email, telephone (including SMS) or fax for these purposes. Your confirmation emails (which may include details of flight bookings, travel documents, recruitment processes, employment and/or human resources or other services booked through our website) may include marketing material which we may feel will be of interest to you from other third parties. We may also use and analyze the information and/or data that we collect so that we can review, administer, support, improve and develop our business and the services which we offer.

To whom we disclose your personal information

Kam Air does not sell or trade your personal information to third parties. We may share information about you as follows:

If you are a customer, your personal data (including sensitive personal data) has been provided to us for the purposes of: making a reservation; recording and issuing a booking; issuing a boarding pass and other purposes associated with or incidental to your carriage. You automatically authorize us to retain and/or use such data and to transmit to and/or to share it with: our own offices, our authorized agents, service providers, approved contractors, our other companies and/or brands, our affiliates, anyone to whom we transfer our rights and duties; third party companies offering related services (including, for example, car rental, hotels, and ancillary services), governments and government agencies, credit/debit card and other payment card companies, and other airlines or providers of such related services.

All credit/debit cards’ details or information will NOT be collected, stored, sold, shared, rented or leased to any third parties.

Kam Air will use your information to provide and personalize our service. We will also use your contact details to communicate with you. We may use your information to send you special offers, travel deals, and news about Kam Air’s products and services or those of relevant companies which we think may be of interest to you. We may contact you by post, email, telephone (including SMS) or fax for these purposes. We may also use and analyze the information that we collect so that we can review, administer, support, improve, and develop our business and services.

Kam Air may also disclose your personal information as permitted or required by law. This could include disclosure outside the UAE. For example, Kam Air will disclose personal information to those governmental bodies who have authority to obtain it, in order to comply with a warrant or subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and to comply with record production requirements.

To customs and/or immigration departments or other regulatory authorities in your country of departure and/or destination in order to comply with the law in those countries.

Kam Air only shares your personal information to the extent required for the performance of such services. Kam Air has implemented safeguards to ensure that our service providers treat personal information in a way that is consistent with the terms of this privacy policy and that it is never used except to fulfil services to Kam Air.

Imortant Information

Ticket: this ticket is non transferable and valid on Kam Air (RQ) flights only.

Reconfirmation & Date Change: Is subject to booking conditions, read the terms and conditions of booking before buying your ticket online.

Checked in baggage allowances: 30 KG on International flights / 20 KG on Domestic flights. The two-piece concept is given to guests coming from or going to USA/Canada i.e. 2 pieces of baggage whose weight is less than 46 Kg, each piece not more than 23 Kg. The combined dimensions of the 2 pieces (L+B+H) should be 106 inches or less. The larger of the two not more than 62 inches. This allowance is irrespective of the fare basis and given to both classes of travel.

Hand Baggage: One bag of maximum 7 Kg with the maximum dimension of 50x40x20 cm. more baggage to be checked in.

Check-in: Passengers are requested to be at Kam Air’s airport Check-in counter minimum 3 Hours prior to scheduled departure. Kam Air will not be responsible for late reporting of passengers.

i.Counter opens 3 hours prior to scheduled departure

ii.Counter closes 45 minutes prior to scheduled departure.

Traveling Documentation: traveler must ensure that his/her passport, health requirements, visa and other necessary documents are valid and meet the requirements of immigration for departure airport and at destination airport. Failure to pass the check-in counter or not report for boarding due to non-compliance of immigration requirement will cause the offloading of passenger and baggage from the flight without any claim or responsibility against Kam Air and ticket conditions will apply. You should carry a copy of this booking confirmation while you travel as it may be required for immigration purposes.

NOSHOW Passenger: reporting late or fail to travel on booked flight will be considered as NOSHOW, penalties as per fare rules will be applied at the time of rebooking or refunding.

Online Tickets: in order to board the flight, passengers who purchased the ticket from www.kamair.com or other booking websites with their Credit cards, are requested to present the card used for the purchase of ticket at the Airport during check-in. If it is not possible to present the card used in person, a photocopy of the front of the card along with a hand written authorization signed by the cardholder may be carried by the passenger and presented to a Kam Air representative at the airport.

Refund:

Subject to fare and fare rules.

If you wish to cancel your flight you must contact us in advance. All changes must be made at least 24 hours prior the flight departure; such cancellations may only be made by the customer named in the booking.

We will credit your balance (if there is any) of your fare due after deduction of cancellation Refund fee.

All the refunds of any transaction’s amount against any purchase through this website would be refunded to the original mode of payment.

We reserve the right to make a refund in the same manner and the same currency used to pay for the Service.

Security

We take appropriate steps to protect the personal information you share with us. When you book a flight or enter personally identifying information, your details are transmitted across the internet securely using high-grade encryption (128 bit SSL). We have implemented technology and security features to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. We also follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us to prevent unauthorized access should we be required to disclose sensitive information to you, we may request proof of identity in adherence with our security procedures before we are able to do so.

In the circumstances set out in this policy where Kam Air passes your information to a third party, we will ensure that the security measures that such party has in place in relation to the processing of your data are at least as stringent as those employed by Kam Air . This does not apply where we are required by law to pass your information to a third party.

We will retain your information for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires.

Tracking site usage

We use tracking software to monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage and to gather certain information like the number and frequency of visitors to the site. This information (which may include the URL you just came from, the URL you next go to, what browser you are using and your IP address) is used to develop the design and layout of the site to better meet the needs of visitors to www.Kamair.com. We only use such data in the aggregate. This software does not capture any personally identifying information.

This information is also used to analyze patterns and improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customize our site's content, layout and services.

By using our website you give your explicit consent for us to collect this data and information and/or use it for the sales and services provided by Kam Air.

Cookies

Our website uses cookies.

A ‘cookie’ is a small bit of data used by a browser to store information. These enable Kam Air to provide you with more personalized services on any future bookings. Cookies can be deleted from your hard drive if you wish. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to prevent this option. Even without a cookie you can use most of the features on our website. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. In choosing to access our website you give your explicit consent and agree for us to use them.

Links

Our website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices and/or the security of websites not operated by Kam Air. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information and data collected by www.kamair.com

Changes to the privacy policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post the changes on our website so you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. This privacy policy may be amended by Kam Air from time to time and at its sole discretion. Use of the website after the effective date of the amendments constitutes explicit consent and acceptance of the amended terms and conditions. We reserve the right to apply the amended terms to the information and/or data we have already collected, subject to any legal constraints.

If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this manner.

Minors accessing our web site

You confirm to Kam Air that you are of the applicable legal age or over to access and use this website in accordance with its terms. If a minor (according to applicable laws) has provided Kam Air with information without consent of a parent or guardian, the parent or guardian can contact Kam Air to remove it.

News and updates

We will occasionally inform you about our special offers and new services via your e-mail address. You only receive our e-mails regarding news and special offers once you subscribe to this service. If you do not wish to receive these e-mails, you can unsubscribe at any time. Once you have unsubscribed, your e-mail address will be removed from the distribution list.

Applicable law

This privacy policy shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the Emirate of Dubai, United Arab Emirates. Any dispute under in relation to or in connection with it shall be submitted to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of the Emirate of Dubai, United Arab Emirates.
